It happened again!
There are reports from
every sector that
まただ！
各地の連絡班から次々に→
our comrades are being ambushed
one after another!
仲間が闇討ちされてるという
情報が入ってきている！
現場は　大混乱だ。　敵が見えない！
There's confusion everywhere!
We don't know who the enemy is!
（シカク）どういうことだ？
夜襲の動きは　なかったはずだ。
What's going on?!
A night raid is supposed
to have been ruled out!
On top of that, we added security and
positioned Sensory-type ninja…
それに　防御を張り
感知タイプを置いていながら→
なんで　敵が見つけられない！？
Why can't we detect the enemy?!
毒か　何かか？
Is it some kind of poison?
死体の状態は！？
What's the condition of the corpses?
All of them have external wounds.
皆　外傷が　あるそうだ。
物理的なものだ。
They're physical attacks.
幻術で　連合の忍を
操っている以外に　ないな…。
No doubt they're controlling
Allied shinobi with genjutsu.
イタチか！？
Could it be Itachi?
Hold on! We just got word from
the Medical Corps.
待て！　医療部隊から連絡だ。
The enemy looks to be…
敵の正体は→
White Zetsu transformed into
Allied Force shinobi!
白いゼツが　連合の忍に
変化しているもよう！
They're able to mirror chakra imprints!
チャクラまで真似る術を使うようだ！
どおりで…。
That explains it…
どうやら　昼間の戦いで→
So during the day battle,
if one of our shinobi got
his chakra absorbed,
そいつに　チャクラを吸い取られた忍は
そっくりに変化されてしまう。
White Zetsu can transform
into him completely!
What should we do,
Shikaku of the Leaf?
どうする！？　木ノ葉のシカク！
こっちは
敵味方の見分けが　つかないうえ→
There is no way we can weed out
who is friend and who is foe!
How will we prepare for
the battle at dawn?
夜明けの開戦準備も　できないぞ！
If we don't find
the enemy immediately,
すぐに
敵を見つける対策をしなければ→
we'll not only lose precious time,
時間とともに
死者は　どんどん増え続けるぞ！
but our own men will
become casualties!
In the end, they could
end up killing each other!
しまいにゃ　仲間どうしで
殺り合うようになる！
So this is the power of White Zetsu.
（マブイ）これが
白ゼツの能力だったのですね。
The battle during the day was
simply to set up the night…
昼間の戦いは　この夜のための
準備ってことですね。
これが　敵の狙いだった。
This was the enemy's true motive.
Aesthetics of an Artist
（オキスケ）敵の動きはありません。
There's no sign of enemy movement.
（ミフネ）うむ…　だが　油断はするな。
Okay, but stay alert.
はい　見張りは
密に立てています。
Yes. I have look-outs
posted everywhere.
止まれ！　何者か！？
（黒ツチ）味方だ。
Halt! Who goes there?!
I'm an ally.
第二部隊　岩隠れ黒ツチ
捕虜との交渉役で来た。
Kurotsuchi of the Hidden Stone,
from the Second Company.
I've come to speak with the prisoner.
交代しよう。
I'm here to relieve you.
おう　助かる。
Okay. Thanks.
アンタも少し休め。
俺たちが見張っている。
Get some rest. We'll keep watch.
（カンクロウ）そうだな。
Okay.
♪～
((デイダラ：究極芸術を
そう何度も世に出すのは→
It's so tacky to exhibit
one's Ultimate Art, over and over!
だせえと思ってたが
しかたがねえ！　うん！
But I guess I have no choice, hmm!
(ううっ　雷遁！？))
Lightning Style?!
《雷遁に弱いってのは
気をつけてたってのによう》
I was being careful too,
since I'm susceptible to
the Lightning Style.
Deidara… Deidara.
（ゼツ）デイダラ。
気安く
オイラの名を呼ぶんじゃねえ！
Stop casually calling out
my name like that!
僕だよ　ゼツだ。
It's me, Zetsu.
ゼツ　お前か。
Zetsu? Is that you?!
キミは　おもしろかったからさ
昔のよしみで助けてやるよ。
You were a fun guy.
I'm going to help you
for old time's sake.
ありがてえ　早く…　早く。
Thanks. Quickly!
Hurry.
ちょっと待ってよ。
Hold on a second…
（黒ツチ）へえ　あれか？
あの中？
Oh that? In there?
なんだ？
What is it?
デイダラ兄　生きてるか？
So Big Bro Deidara, you still alive?
死んでんだよ
その声　黒ツチか？
I'm dead.
That voice… Is that you, Kurotsuchi?
昔のよしみで
助けにきたのか？
Did you come to rescue me
for old time's sake?
昔のよしみで
アタイが派遣されたんだろうけど→
I was sent here because
we used to be friends,
話は逆だ。
助けてもらいたくて来た。
but the situation's just
the opposite now.
I came because I need your help.
ハッ　なんだそりゃ？
岩の尋問か…。
Huh? What do you mean by that?
She's interrogating
the Hidden Stone ninja.
薬師カブトはどこだ？
Where is Kabuto Yakushi?
（デイダラ）知るか
知ってたって言わねえな。
How should I know!
I wouldn't tell you even if I knew, hmm.
なあ　兄
カブトに無理やり生き返らされて→
Look, Bro…
Kabuto brought you back to life
便利に使われてるんだぜ。
and is now using you at
his convenience.
死んだんだからさ
昔のことは忘れて→
You're dead, so the least
you can do is forget the past,
少しくらい
アタイらに協力しろよ。
and cooperate with us a little.
カブトは　オイラに→
Kabuto gave me an opportunity
to acquire the Super Ultimate Art.
更なる超究極芸術への
チャンスをくれたんだ。
じゃあ　うちはサスケはどこ？
All right.
Then where is Sasuke Uchiha?
サスケだと？
アイツも穢土転生されたってのか？
Sasuke, you say?
Are you saying
he was reanimated, as well?
サスケ　死んでねえし！
Sasuke's not dead!
バカ言うんじゃねえ！　アイツは
オイラの究極芸術で死んでんだ。
Don't be ridiculous!
I killed him with my Ultimate Art!
だって　アタイ見たぜ。
But I saw him.
兄が死んだ後も
サスケがピンピンして→
After you died Bro,
Sasuke was alive and well.
雷影たちと戦ってたところ。
He was fighting with the Raikage
and the others.
((すげえ…))
A-Amazing.
アイツは　今　暁のメンバーで
忍者連合の大敵だ。
He joined the Akatsuki and
is an enemy of the Allied Forces.
アイツが暁だと？
He's with the Akatsuki?!
なあ？
ま　まあね。
Right?
Huh?! Yeah, I guess.
なんだ　そりゃ
サスケが生きてる。
What's with that?
Sasuke's alive?
And he's a member of Akatsuki?
しかも暁　ふざけんな！
You've gotta be kidding.
((死んで　オイラは芸術になる！
In death, I will become art.
今までにない爆発は→
This never-before-seen explosion
この地に
今までにない傷跡を残し→
will leave a never-before-seen scar
on this land.
そして　オイラの芸術は→
And…! My art will win
never-before-seen admiration!
今までにない称賛を
受けるだろう。
さあ　怯えろ。
驚嘆しろ　絶望しろ！
Now, tremble with fear!
Be in awe! Despair!
泣きわめけ！
オイラの芸術は…。
Scream!
My art is…
喝！
(爆発だ！))
An explosion!
あれで死なねえわけがねえ。
There's no way
he could still be alive!
（黒ツチ）だから　生きてるって。
I'm telling you he's alive.
オイラの究極芸術だぞ？
That was my Ultimate Art!
（黒ツチ）芸術っていっても
誰も気にしてねえし！
Nobody cares about art.
サスケの野郎　なんなんだよ　アイツは？
Sasuke, that bastard!
What's with that guy?!
Wasn't he in awe?
驚嘆しなかったのか
怯えなかったのか？
Didn't he tremble with fear?
Didn't he despair?
絶望しなかったのか？
なんだこれはと
叫ばなかったのか？
Didn't he scream,
"What the hell is this?!"?
((サスケ：土遁は雷遁に弱い。
The Earth Style is vulnerable
to the Lightning Style.
アンタの爆弾は　雷遁をくらえば
起爆しなくなる。
Your explosives won't detonate
against my Lightning Style.
(それが弱点なんだろ？))
Isn't that your weakness?
ふざけんじゃねえ！　サスケ！
Screw you, Sasuke!
いつまでも　雷遁にやられてる
オイラじゃねえぞ！
Your Lightning Style won't
hold me down forever!
グッ！
ミフネ隊長　本部より急電！
Commander Mifune!
An urgent message from Headquarters!
連合内に敵が紛れ込み
暗殺を繰り広げているもよう。
The enemy has infiltrated
the Allied Forces
and are assassinating people!
各部隊に混乱が広がっています。
Chaos is spreading within
all the companies!
この部隊の
安否を問われていますが？
Is this company in any danger?
今のところ　異常はない。
Not at the moment.
はっ！　そう返信します。
Yes, sir! I will relay your reply.
ミフネ様！　先刻の岩のくノ一は？
Sir, what about
the Hidden Stone kunoichi earlier?
敵とは思えなんだが。
I don't think she's an enemy.
兄？　おい　聞いてんのか　兄！
Bro?
Hey, are you listening, Bro?
Answer me!
返事しろ！　あ～もう！
埒あかねえ！
This isn't getting anywhere!
開けろ　これ。　直に話す。
Open it. I want to speak
with him directly.
開けますか？
You want me to open it?
おい。
Hey.
はっ！
Sir!
山。
は？
Mountain.
Huh?
山！
…の　あなたの空遠く？
Mountain…
Distant skies?
うわっ！
え？
川だ。
侍は…。
It's "River."
Damn samurai!
（ゼツ）単純すぎだよ。
貴様ら！
You're so predictable.
You bastards!
ゼツってヤツだ！
なに！？
They're Zetsu!
What?!
気をつけろ！
ソイツは　チャクラを吸い取る！
Careful! They'll absorb your chakra!
♪～
芸術は爆発だ！
Art is…an explosion.
デイダラ…。
Deidara!
How?! Why didn't the Lightning Style
seal his Explosion Style?!
なぜだ？　雷遁で　爆遁は
封じていたはずじゃん。
フンッ！
あれで　雷遁を逃がしたのか？
Is that how you channeled
the Lightning Style away?
なんで　あんなものが
傀儡の中に？
What was that doing
inside the puppet?!
僕のおかげだね。
It was thanks to me…
ゼツ。
なに？
Zetsu.
What?
逃げるぞ！
え？　待って！
Let's get out of here!
Huh? Wait!
逃がすかよ！
ったく！
Don't let him get away!
Man, he's troublesome
even when he's dead!
死んでからも
迷惑かけやがるぜ！
捕虜のデイダラが逃走した！
ゼツという仲間も一緒だ。　捕らえろ。
The prisoner, Deidara,
has escaped.
He's with his comrade, Zetsu.
Apprehend them!
オキスケ！
それがしの不覚。
Okisuke.
I will take full responsibility
for my blunder, I swear!
この責任は　必ずや！
今は　悔やむときではない　追え！
はっ！
This is not the time for regrets.
After them!
Yes, sir!
なんで逃げるのさ？
やっつけちゃおうよ。
Why are we running?
Let's kill them!
オイラの起爆粘土がもうねえんだ。
どっかで補充しねえと。
I'm out of Detonating Clay.
I need to get more somewhere.
あっ！　来た！
Uh-oh… They're coming!
♪～
You're in my way!
邪魔だ！
前からも！
In front, too!
Damn it!
チクショウ！
お前　相変わらず弱いな。
Still weak as ever, aren't you?
あれは　時間稼ぎの戦い方さ。
That was a tactic to
give us more time.
《カブト：封印を
抜け出したようだね》
Looks like you escaped the seal.
カブトか？
Kabuto!
（カブト）さすがだね。　回収するよ。
I would've expected nothing less.
I'll take that back.
Wait!
《待て！　オイラの究極芸術が
全否定されたんだ。
My Ultimate Art was
completely rejected!
このままじゃ　死ねねえ！
死んでるけど。　うん》
I can't die like this…
even if I'm already dead. Hmm.
そこで戦うというのかい？
You intend to stand and fight there?
《オイラは
超究極芸術を完成させる》
I'm going to perfect
my Super Ultimate Art!
芸術家の考えはわからないな。
I just don't understand
how you artists think.
だけど　インテリは
芸術家を庇護するものさ。
But intellectuals have
to protect artists.
アイツは…。
That's…
（中吉）逃げろ。　食い止める。
Get away. I'll hold them off.
任せるぞ　中吉！
I'll leave them to you, Chukichi!
霜隠れの術。
Hidden Frost Jutsu.
何だ　こりゃ？
What the hell?!
Where is he hiding?
どこに隠れた？
であ～っ！
多いな。
That's…a lot of 'em.
He's gone!
消えた！
おのれ！
Curses!
感知しました。
ミフネ隊長　向こうです！
I sense them!
Commander Mifune!
They went that way!
行くぞ！
Let's go.
どこまで逃げるの？
How much farther
are we going to run?
粘土だ　うん。
I need clay, hmm!
土の中に
粘土のある場所を見つける。
I need to find a place
with clay in the soil.
そんなら僕に任せてよ。
Leave that to me.
好きに戦えばいい　デイダラ。
Fight as you see fit, Deidara.
Freedom suits you well.
キミには自由が似合う。
それに　僕は忙しくなる。
Besides, I'm going to be busy.
デイダラ兄が起爆粘土を
手に入れる前に捕まえないと→
Unless we catch Big Bro Deidara
before he finds some clay,
やっかいなことになるぞ。
this could get troublesome.
前は雲のオモイが雷遁で
爆発を抑えてくれたが→
Previously, Omoi of the Cloud
contained the explosion
with his Lightning Style,
アイツは今　別の部隊だ。
but he's is in a different unit now.
この隊に雷遁使いは？
Do we have anyone in this unit
who can handle lightning?
第５部隊は２つに分かれた。
Fifth Company split into two.
この隊の主戦力は侍で→
Our company's main weapon
is samurai.
忍は感知　封印　情報といった
支援班しかおらぬ。
Our only ninja are sensory, sealing,
and intel support personnel.
ミフネ隊長　雷遁なら私が使えます。
Commander Mifune,
I am able to do Lightning Style.
よし。
Good…
They're coming, Deidara!
Our pursuers!
来たよ　デイダラ　追っ手だ！
What?!
なに！？　起爆粘土は
まだ　これっぽっちなんだぞ。
I've only managed to get
this much Detonating Clay!
散！
Scatter!
雷遁！
Lightning Style!
What's happening?!
何だ？
兄のヤツ！
Did Big Bro—?!
Under us!
下だ！
地雷か？
Land mines!
Jump!
飛べ！
喝！
オイラの邪魔はさせねえ！
You're not gonna stop us!
そらっ！
ハァーッ！
Take that!
足りねえな　うん。
Not enough, hmm.
This is art!
これが芸術だ。
兄が爆発するぞ！
Big Bro's gonna explode.
You have to keep discharging it!
流し続けねえとダメじゃん。
もっと強力な雷遁じゃねえと！
We need a more powerful
Lightning Style!
Th-This is the best I can do!
こ　これが俺の精一杯だ！
Lord Mifune!
ミフネ様！
喝！
お～い　デイダラ。
Hey, Deidara…
なんだ　こりゃ。
Hey, what's happening to me?
A reanimated body is immortal.
穢土転生の体は不死身だからね。
In a way, you're like
a walking Detonating Clay Bomb.
ある意味　キミは歩く起爆粘土だ。
やっぱりか。
I suspected that.
How tacky! The despair, hmm!
だせえ！　絶望だ　うん。
なんで？
Why?
芸術は一瞬の輝き。
Art is a moment of brilliance,
blossoms that scatter all at once.
一瞬にして散る花。
だが　この体じゃ散れねえ。
But this body can't scatter!
究極芸術を超える
超究極芸術を　探すぞ。
I'm going to find
a Super Ultimate Art
that transcends
the Ultimate Art, hmm.
うん。
うう…。
ちくしょう！　兄ぃのヤツ…。
Damn you, Bro!
ミフネ様　どこです？
Lord Mifune? Where are you?
ミフネ様！
Lord Mifune!
The holes left by his landmines
became trenches.
あやつの地雷の跡が
塹壕代わりになった。
起爆粘土を持ったデイダラ兄は
ハンパねえ。
Bro Deidara wasn't very thorough
with his Detonating Clay, was he?
作戦がいるぞ。
We'll need a plan.
絶縁できれば
雷遁を逃がさないようにできる。
With insulation,
we could keep him from channeling
away the Lightning Style.
The problem is
our Lightning Style wielder.
問題は　その雷遁使いだ。
But…I'm not…
しかし　私では…。
おぬしは感知に専念しろ。
You just concentrate on
sensing their whereabouts.
本部に増援を要請しますか？
Shall I request Headquarters
for reinforcements?
増援を待つ時間はない。
We don't have time to wait
for reinforcements.
現有勢力でやる。
We'll do this with
the personnel we have.
《どうする？
What am I going to do?
不死身のこの体と
オイラの美学が合致しねえ。
This immortal body and
my aesthetic are incompatible.
Sasori might be able
to do something.
サソリの旦那なら
なんかあるかもしれねえが→
さっさと行っちまったしな。
But he went off quickly.
孤独だ。
I'm all alone.
だが芸術家は
そもそも孤独だ。　うん》
But artists are loners
to begin with, hmm.
地雷埋めてきたよ。
I buried the landmines.
どう？　なんか浮かんだ？
Well? Got any ideas?
芸術は　そう簡単に浮かばねえよ。
Art doesn't come to one that easily.
Especially not a Super Ultimate Art!
ましてや…　超究極芸術だぞ。
♪～
サスケ！？
Sasuke?!
えっ　なんで？
Why are you here?
お前らか…。
It's you guys…
テメエ！　なんで生きていた？
Bastard! Why are you alive?!
ナルトはどこだ？
Where's Naruto?
I don't know!
知らねえよ！　って
今は　オイラを見やがれ　うん！
Right now, pay attention to me, hmm!
My business is with Naruto.
用があるのはナルトだ。
Damn it, not that again!
あ～！　テメエ　またかよ！
イタチの次は　ナルトか？
First Itachi, now Naruto?!
You really don't give
a damn about me, do you?!
あくまで　オイラは
眼中にないってのか！
ない。
Nope.
テメエ！
Bastard!
They're coming!
追っ手だ。
じゃあな。
See ya.
あっ　待ちやがれ！
デイダラ！
Stop!
Deidara!
逃がすな！
Don't let them get away!
You're not getting away!
逃がさねえ。
デイダラ　待て。
Deidara! Wait!
そのサスケ　なんだか…。
Sasuke didn't seem…
うおっ！
This time,
I'll make you tremble with fear!
今度こそ怯えさせてやる
驚嘆させてやる。
You'll be awed!
絶望させてやる。
You'll feel despair.
そのすました顔を歪ませてやる。
I'll wipe that smug expression
off your face!
ハァ…　あっ！
あ…　ああ～！　うん！
そうか　そこに　あそこに！
ハハハハ。
I see!
There! Over there!
I knew it. Your weakness
isn't Lightning Style, Bro.
やっぱ兄の弱点は→
It's your stupid obsession with art!
雷遁ってより
芸術バカなとこだぜ。
黒ツチ？
Kurotsuchi?!
あっ　テメエら　これ何のマネだ。
Bastards! What's the meaning of this?
喝！
不発だと！？
A dud?
Dammit!
クソ！
そんな刀じゃ
オイラの芸術は止まらねえ。
That sword won't stop my art!
くっ！　侍が雷遁だと！？
A samurai using Lightning Style?!
雷遁ではない。
It's not Lightning Style.
A storage cell… Looks like
you know how to use one.
蓄電池というものだが
使えるようだな。
使えねえよ。
I don't!
What the—?!
なに！？
This is all bedrock, Bro.
ここら一帯は岩盤なんだよ
兄。
The sword can't penetrate.
刀は通らない
通っても雷遁を逃がさない。
Even if it could, it won't let
the Lightning Style discharge.
うっ　クソ　離せ　この野郎！
Damn it! Hey! Let me go!
All right.
よし。
それで　兄　本物のサスケは
今どこにいるんだ？
テメエ　黒ツチ！　オイラを
バカにしてんじゃねえぞ　おら！
サスケのマネなんかしやがって
似てたじゃねえか　クソ！
あ～あ　あたいが　デイダラ兄から→
何か聞きだそうってのは
もうムリだ。
すっかり　へそ曲げてら。
戻るぞ　元の戦線を維持する。
本部に報告せよ。
隊長　それ返していただければと。
ん？　おお。
もう迷惑かけんじゃねえぞ
デイダラ兄　じゃあな。
う～ん…。
いけるな　うん。
超究極芸術のテーマは決まった。
そこに顔があっても
いいじゃないか。
芸術は永遠に死なねえ。
オイラは死んでるけど　うん。
＜　ごはんのおともが
大好きな豆助＞
豆助　きょうの　ごはんのおともは
これと　これよ
＜　それは意外な組み合わせ＞
＜　ごはんのおいしさを
引き出してくれる　ゆかり＞
＜　これに合わせるのが…＞